so yeah sure what to do your work area
updates
there's a very short lecture file
that doesn't say much more than taiwan
rob's
p_f_ persons of his
luxury golds
and create directory for today
right everybody i just updated the
material posit orig so if you've
grab it is go ahead and do another
poland update
it's not very exciting
there's just basically free directory
make a symbolic link which you guys
haven't done before but just
if it works
then run the three debbie gets
forgets go ahead and get started today
bochco pref well from applied to useless
right
yes all
the artist sister gopac tapes which i
don't feel other so i'm glad you guys
incoming student on this one
saw the entire city with the wall
and i would have liked both brown and
okay
frank thanks
okay so
eckardt's a robb russell higham
with a small company market
uh... work on the mind of the things
using satellite remote sensing data to
com
monitor for speculation
deforestation
what about things and also generally
interested in
just because they don't happen
and that's how
treatments are working together
i guess but at the meeting i want to do
is just the kind of exposure to the
basics of our dual experience just
typing in our commands and see what
happens
uh... exposed to
the flavor of the language it's a
different kind of language probably than
uh...
views before
anyone usar
will decline
looking for help restricted
well it is just up
first get a little intro hampson
ventures some background information
some things on the web
but but the attention functions
and then will home
dismissed successes
a couple of years ago i talked of course
it was uh... state fourteen weeks and
each week we have different topic
we use our
and i tried this if you try as before
using other languages
ideal matlab things like that
some of our work the best
for various reasons it's really easy to
get spun up on
it has
premature weeping already right there
it turned out once we got the basics
down it was really easy to sort of built
on top of the basics
you know week you can see record like a
huge range of stuff
just doing basic stats
declassification problems
week six dealing with messy data
week seven bootstrapping interact ninety
some you know pretty fancy
really practically
usable statistics
since this is about to be
as sophisticated as we thought going in
monte-carlo approaches
kind of data introvert time series
analysis neural networks fish stocks and
so on even image processing which
and usually i thought you know i was
gonna be fairly weak i miss processing
but it turned out there quite a lot of
up things available in itunes http
so many point here is
fairly short span of time
you can use our to do
lots of different things
across the uh... did an awesome spectrum
right so what is our
ours language for data analysis and
visualization
does both those things really well
the vendors are you know it's free
it has a lot of functions ready to go
without having to
yetta adams
if you want add-ons their
over three thousand
packages available
secured a number of things
and a large developer needs a community
which means it's changing it's becoming
more solid than even at our years it's
been around a long time
if there's not something billboard are
right now there will be to the problem
so that you know if you disadvantages
for me than now primarily pipeline
programs like these python from lost
applications at work on
i find that the arson taxes a little
awkward it's hard to get used to
it's as a kind of up
sorted out
complex hierarchy of objects
too little sometimes hard to understand
what dot
the object is that you're working with
it doesn't want to tell you what it is
as much as python objects to
when you really want to give an honest
and what's going on are to be a little
it's a little opaque
but beyond that you know for a large
datasets
uh... maybe not the best
for non standard formats
like if somebody just hands use some
crazy data logger format
i think there are as not as easy to use
as playful
and of course like a lot of other
languages
if you just doing loops an arms control
so just let it or some
resources that are available on the web
the first so i'm i'm not gonna click on
this one but
this is the one of my favorite online
our introduction to thirty
that's got a lot of peter's
a lot of stuff it walks you through the
basics really well
on this one
cycle when is the
remain our website from marion click on
manuals and then there's a lot of
documentation one interesting stuff
this one in particular i think is useful
this art intro dot pbf
from my course i've got a bunch of
materials that i am currently in the
process of cleaning up
uh... they're a lot of uh...
and said that if we're not done as far
as putting
things into separate directories
that assignments and datasets
lectures
you're going to the semester
scripts
phil phil look through this stuff and if
there's something in there you want to
use it if you want to ask you about
you can do that
also
that there's a blog
which i just discovered actually in the
sky water really great stuff
let's listen
so it's pretty up to date and
you can just sort of foot through there
and see what people are doing like a
sort of some today
do your random variables into groove
more
you check that out
and this i think is their actually
uh... wave files making sounds from
davidson concludes in two days
uh... then there's this graphics gallery
which actually find really useful
on the sky
if i have a connection to be able to see
it
who is a graphics gallery
and
you know some of our disco browsing
through here to see it like
apec that some day or night i have an
idea what i want the sort of the product
to look like
uh... this flat news just put through
these and all
italy's gets started you know
i could take something like this are
you know what the bunny and i can make
it
look like ah...
you know what what i want to make it you
know is my dear
here's one that
like a lot when you have uh...
what the very dataset and a lot of
points in a clump together and you want
to see what the correlation really looks
like you know without the over plotting
this is one that
that i use
the plots all the columns of your day
and then indicates or how many points
there are within each of these little
cells
uh... judges introducing what the data
types are in our
i mentioned that
it so it's a little more complicated and
paper and since they're more different
kinds of things
and are
there are
they're sort of a hierarchy of datatypes
they have what they call sort of
atomic types which have a mood
and then
variable was going to have a
classes courses for class
we don't really need to worry about that
so much
practically speaking day-to-day working
with our
you're going to be using one of these
types of
datatypes so very bold when you sign
something to a veritable it's most
likely going to be one of these things
it's gonna be a factor which is an order
sequence things that all the same type
like
it to the almanac
or all character
on the computer rain
uh... which is essentially a vector
except to commit to a more dimensions
and it doesn't have to be strictly
rectangular convenient
a ragged array
it's essentially vector of doctors
the matrix is
they're more stricter
ru more strict rules apply to matrix
because
matrices are used for
matrix mathematics basically
so they're strictly rectangular
two-dimensional
and have other sort of properties
if they keep track of
a list of sort of the odd one it can be
anything it's like a list of pipeline
comments actually when i use the leaks
uh... a factor and use a lot
factor describes discrete classes
so if you take a bunch of managers and
convert them to factor it doesn't think
of those things as numeric
quantities anymore things of the most
types
so you can classify do that way
you can on group data
and have argue
operations like take averages
do statistical summaries on groups
using these factors
in a different actually one of the most
useful data types
that i've not found
in pipeline i've had to make myself in
python and have been really happy with
what i've made is essentially named list
of actors or factors it's like a
spreadsheet
so in those what columns are the columns
are the same type
and it can do operations on the cons
independently
briefing slice
rows and columns out
where you can do a switch it's it's a
really it's a real useful very commonly
use
datatype in you can read a csd file for
example right into a different
ours a functional language and that just
means that
the way you do you use it is you take
object to take data you quite functions
to them
com and then you get some data that
comes out
this is sort of up
action to serve a vocabulary list
of our functions from
pick up the second week of my class
succeed we have
a built-in statistical
functions malfunctions graphing
functions
datatypes
conversions texts
lots of other things
and also interestingly hands
it comes on top of the insects which i
think it's kind of unusual
you can just type
letters your word for the alphabet
sunspots when you get
sunspot data which was built in with
datasets that you can use for just
testing things out for teaching for
but learning style
but you'll see that in them
actual you'll see a lot of stuff i'm
talking about in the uh... exercises
the tricky part two
so we'll get to as much of this is we
get through
elective restricted to
and the first part
introduction to are
and i did this in my first class and it
was
to respect it it's a little you might
think
forty years to just
have someone say you know take the stand
and see what happens
but actually i've found
for myself that's a good way of learning
language comin along the way
their questions about
you do you understand what just happened
you can ask me
but basically the idea is that
redo this work through it and ask
questions as you go on all move around
and we start really just by starting up
our
dispelled like everybody to do that now
okay
you just have to install it
club
you'll see a little prompted looks like
the greater than some
the basic idea is to see prompt
looks like the green and signed
and that's where you'd type arguments
so there are different ways you can have
always liked
python depois you can interact with our
you can't just uh... have a terminal
session where you take command and see
what happens
or you can write a script and run the
script
uh... what will be doing is just like in
the commands being returned to see what
happens
couple of quick things
so the first thing is at the prompt
treatment return
and c_n_n_
there are other things that followed
uh...
doing some arithmetic and then you go
from there
one of things you see is that
consignment operator our use
is the equal sign
a lot of people and our world
use
less than an hour hate them
it's a style thing and are allows you to
do both
preferred people sign
if you go forth and use our
i would suggest you people sign i just
it makes sense to me his something
that's one character instead of
uh...
comic character is a downside
with assignment
you guys have done
programming so
and what one as we talked about goods
are people that were new to programming
is the idea of assignments when you say
x equals three
you're taking them to be
in your story into variable x
and that's uh... beginning
over the things that happened
phone
groupings about
and who knows a lot of times vietnam's
sometimes when you do something it will
in net result to the screen like if you
if you don't have an assignment
so if i just say sign the point one
return
instead of assigning it's a very bold
innovative in preventing assignment
value on the screen you'll see that
underneath
the promptly return
if i say
why equals
slide point one
then you don't see anything
right 'cause it's a sign the results of
this
variable y
subsequently declared why not returning
you'll see you at the value
of lives
your question
like python
are treats
all numeric values and the same in a way
so if you do
divided by three it's going to do
integer division
if you want a force it to do
floating-point division
give it a decimal point out one or both
and the other thing is
want to see what happens
you can break anything just
start typing stopped
sure see what happens without the period
or with the period
well that's interesting
i did not take the letter q now irene
so what did you do
again
that is and that gives you letters here
to do any of the question
no one can although i wasn't
you wanted to see what happened if you
cut the question mark
i can't
white
so that's the continuation
if you see a plus
an actual you'll see that ah...
actually when you get to the bottom of
the first page even
you'll see that if you uh...
if you enter a top
an expression
and you get return before it's done
before it can actually perform a
calculation like a perfect three-plus
and i had returned and i've done
so it'll give you a plus sign on the
next one
conflict three possible
and if you you give it something
here to traces
a lot of times i'll get to this point
because i have a whole bunch of stuff
here
and i'll get the plus an object i have
no idea electives fifty practices i
don't know which one
i left out
i'll just head up
escape for controlling officer
the control ceo risky p
freak you out of the swine continuation
on
if you see that
i mean if you know what you need to try
to finish the
yeah
so the first the first letter on the
second line
is not nineteen nineteen turned to the
world to do to forty percent vision
twenty-six yet
so what it's doing here it is it's
coming up how many roosevelt but you
have book report
essentially how many items of i'll put
you have
and what
what idm
begins on that route
and this is our item number nineteen
the asi that's a little confusing that's
that's
if u arm
it's this uh... continuation mark
so if i type three plus in his return
then i have it completed my uh...
expression if it doesn't know what the
calculated
so the plus you see down here underneath
is actually asking me for more stuff
which is fifteen can be confusing when
you first starting cuz it looks like a
plus
so typically when i see
so if i said three-plus
figures mean a plus
son underneath
um... allows i'm so happy to give
whatsup rent the season things and
uh... it's you'd be just messed
something up back into the country
control c
gets me out of it might get you out of
it too
uh... or you can just complete the line
plus unsafe or or five
that gives me the answer
the other thing
someone noticed is
what do these things in the brackets
here
well this is just telling you know it's
just giving you a kind of a running
count
of the items that have been out
letters returns acts probably et al
factor of characters
so it's saying the first item starts
here in the first row
and then this is actually overrunning
the screen
coming out there like that
so this is still the first row
then the second row starts at the
twentieth item
twenty three one three two so on
twenty-six
the first one is one n are starts coming
with one
that's another thing that's different
from other languages
thank you for bringing that up
so i can say
x equals letters
what's x
at zero
exit zero just tells me the datatype
ticks one give me a letter
fixed-wing six
that argument v
yes
next
programs
it does it differently alexi
thing
you remind myself with us 'cause i've
been using them
on the platform for a while
furthers x
simply said
g
the behavior the minus sign is
interesting
e burger
and you're the next one
trivial or not i will continue to keep
gotten the first time celebrity national
some more pounds
popping thing from different
your standoff
that's a big horn
also on the flip side of that is you
have an idea what kinds of things can be
different
and you say
how does this language to array
subscription like
doesn't look like purchase it does have
a minus contains a
but a minus sign in their and what what
if i do
what will happen
python you can put a minus sign in the
arraignment producer behavior
an r
it gives you some other behavior
and i actually spend like right now i
spent a lot of time just write stuff
so if i go on camera using
python
or if i go on from not using our i'd
suggest sit and mike
type a bunch of things and i always have
an interactive window open
even if i'm running along
you know really long period of
processing script
you know we have some pretty big ones
i get to something that really should
know but i've forgotten
you no longer type in just a make sure
that if i say
to a certain kind of slicer certain kind
of
syntax it's really doing the things
moved
orchids betsy the leather seat
this is a that's an archive of the
wreckage
it's actually function
and i wouldn't name a function in my
language with just one letter but
they have and that's called
it sees fit kat made of the concurrently
operator
by say see
one come into kamisetti
it's going to create a vector
of numbers one two three
the presidency
ninety-nine
it's gonna create a vector with just one
thing in it
and the point of that section i think i
might have a little verbiage about it
the point that section is that
a number is just a vector public one
and our that's different from pipeline
you know python a list of the since its
own that fearless fearless
get one
element analyst journalist with one
element
but in are
the concept of a numeric
of the basic numeric object say a number
it's as a factor discipline
and i see some people are getting error
messages that skid
that's good collects the young man and
china seem you know
kenneth m
languages error messages can be uh...
provide different levels of insight into
what you doing
it's not a stroke
so acting
it's just
sort of wearing
yes indeed all the companies not exits
just
dot is enough
gadget that her people like you who
michael walker
and i still wanted
defend that reviewed of house yeah
right its
it's a valid character
she could basically create andy's
data structures
you want i guess with the basic
datatypes
but they don't they're not referenced in
the same way
they're not lifeguard
it's not it's not the same you don't
have
it's not like you have an object with
methods or or attributes that you can
reference that way
sometime functionally
which can be a little weird because
functions like plot for example
they get overridden all the time so if i
have uh...
think that's a time series object
and i supply that thing
i think i'm calling plot
it's a psychological plot
but it's actually been overridden
spots and a special time three format
so that's something i want to know
or denies it
their ways that to find out
but it's doing that
for example
all the documents
our documentation is super strict
you know they have to say
to have a plot method
to do
and all of the things like these
specialized plot methods have their own
special name to sell it
plot that yes
is that specialized in seconds
generic top talent
it's a little confusing if it is because
usta object-oriented programming
kazakh that kind of his
missiles the kind of
but
soviet with your first question was
to reserve ella characters like it's a
my dot data
missy
one-two-three-four
okay so
podiatry
used to up type on or some other
languages it's that's not indicating
that data as an attribute of mind
because just saying
i have a variable called my that data
it's really common in our people use the
alive still looks weird
not not then or do you see one
okay i don't think so think it's like
quite fun that way
maastricht yeah
right now
one though
all
it should be in al so uh...
discussing what kind of party one direct
line her daughter subjects on steve
regional him
yet that's a no to do now
so when you get to plot
playthings suppressive plot on my arm
uh...
equals
so it's an l another one basically
type is one of the um...
options you can get to the plot function
posing basically what kind of
symbolically to use that's one of one of
the types of with birthplace and biology
there's some
abi says both
caltech helped plot cover remember the
others
soapy
treatment
the three day remember p dole and p
subpoena proponents
self-rule on
and the provoked
to pinpoint of light
plot is won the commands with the most
optional
compute do a lot with plot
function just
the basic plan function
if i have
i prefer to use our for simple plotting
if i have a way to get my date out into
a nice
you know the common delimited format
uh... being d_n_a_ out of art
to make a deal
so if i have like us history file on my
through these are
for ferdinand
plots
yet
that's right yeah i mean
um... yes e_s_p_n_'s kind of thing
like biking
spit something out of the intermediate
there or whatever at fifteen
i'd like to do that
if it's you know if it's that kind of
data
and use the map club lived in python
it's just something's going on internal
so that
so the program and i don't want to have
to save data allen switch to our
and i just wanna say
generate a plot so i could see what's
going on
if i'm making a plot
publication presentation trends are
they put a lot upon them to me
the graphics could get
and actually making it treatable it's of
i think it's easier to just
fewer lines of things like him
your map plot led this kind of like
uh... matlab
where you have to be separate commands
for com
so if you want to label on the x-axis
thing and i'm like
okay amai
operating on the axis object horror on
the page object of the whatever and
sitemap level a tend to think about
stuff
women are just tight
title people
why is it four is that the question
higher okay
so let's see let's put back what is it
so wave becky redefined women's it's a
vector and it's got three numbers and
the first time in history and secondhand
forum hunger
because our starts coming
uh... one
invective so that's
uh... and one mystery into this for
and three is a hundred
you think
it's the second value yet
does that make sense to me
i can say texaco als
one two three four five
wanted
x one two three that's a slight sickens
me items wanted
uh... yeah that's how thick
alliance
yes
friends
this kind of this is like what your
question was about attributes of things
this is the only place that you come
across this in our
regularly
the dollar sign is used to access
most commonly uh... columns in the data
so if i say
yeah reached
exp as a data
training
him
so extended a friend contacts
i can see what the column headers are
protecting the incident
i can access
the columns individually by saying x
dubbed
there are other places that those time
pops up but that's the most common
and if you type
uh... somewhere in here i think i get
into the attach function
if you say attach
to that their friends and also to come
for or
let's say uh...
you've got this really big david said
it's all in line
you know one big spreadsheet
theory dollar everything you do is going
to be in there
everything you make it to be in column
something like it or graphics
so you can spend all your time working
in sort in this environment of working
in just a different
you know if it does dollar fine both
time
so what you can do is they attach
i can say patch etx
and now i have available to me
the bill the variables person
and w that i didn't have before
and you can see detach
so that you consider release that those
names
conservatism
the fancy detached
w
and scheme
him
xm
unit
only happens groups competing ties if it
is that but that's because the variable
names x
so i'll
you can override yes he was defeated him
for that
do it but why dot obsolete definitely
he
to see if i typed
t come alive
it's going to go ahead and
give the axis labels
unified
it's going to give it a little uh...
terrible names
so you can override them line uh...
equals
okay
sits
deepti that camel's balkanized nixon
comfortable
people
yet mexico could have just get something
and and you can change when it is
versus having to
knowing that you have to build
even for starters at the building
is that i was wondering l
could make it up
okay
i'll show you what that is
if you'd look at the screen
plants in dayton
compensate type vehicles
it makes
points like scatter plot
closely tied
well
that's just one of the ways you can
change the symbolic hip-hop
eg
that should be natural
no uh... alone he should be nonchalant
go
the outcome
and did you want the base tomorrow
yet set trial i think i don't know but
let's try like ten elegy tent
yet this is pretty common burkhart
across languages um...
blog
ten
if you can't get the latest
and those are you know unsaid
yes if you wanted hyperbolic
coats you can't nothing
i've unsafe i would just start typing
stuff
antennae
and well until five minutes was up and
then i would go
are going to let
taggers eliminated
there is a way to do general topics of
help
uh... is at this
so it's just like math
christian christians
question question math
must've known that at some point and
forgot the venue
uh... so
uh... actually that's because with the
help of god
and the new north road
okay so here's one that i did but this
on the list of disadvantages
googling are that's like
and uh...
darania
at that
well i i had to say
they're great because after the first
thing that comes up from google
so the figure that out somehow
so once they are
this is not my interest
corrosive can
matlab
i didn't do the thing i said a few which
is to just start typing stuck
mhm t
cities like colin rxpop
to go back here
so i would
so it's a test
and colin
with that him
like this
colin liked that yet
and then to start type it up
like um...
people of new york
hyperbolic
coats you can't
i'm actually been authors
latest a c sorry
cyclin
or right
the best way arbitrator again closer
hyperbolic
so high-tech are malfunctions in that
kind of got me close
and i'm right here and that those
so list of stuff
and uh...
such close on
and then they came in a list of
development
it's not is indian answers i would like
doesn't make sense is ok ok
yes one other thing i know see exactly
what i know you know you have multiple
purposes
if i get more than you know too
or one so different things and
computer
and i'm on a quest for or possibly
non-existent
the clinton hyperbolic
so
comparable unknown overused in physics
what yet you had to install package
called g
your account you will
so they only go to places that
party they're part of their site or the
ourselves stuff
so sometimes the answers is that you
have to install package
so and the scans for this thing and
map fortune i would have to install the
ji height
ninety
five percent of the time ideal
installing
policy
project
continues
circles of different size like alan
that's one of my favorite one
electric in circles of different sides
what's what's the five
that uh...
kasra dot
and what he said to me
uh... make this time
know how much i like that
essentially
yeah how far away there from the fear
that limestone
besides sir
you need to be a ski cap
casualties
yeah how do you know
so cut
and that's a variable
and that morning as three different
level so what it does is it splits into
three
people sections
essentially let's take a look
yes those who helped cut
to close by the voters of a restaurant
according to which generally fall
intervals of time by the bricks
so we didn't we didn't have an article
breaks that doesn't help me
divides its in the
meaning that
that's a good question where does cut do
that
so you can specify the breakpoints
so i could actually say
you know what levels to do the breaking
up
if you don't but the question of the
decide compaq think that i thought that
it was
splitting the range evenly so you
wouldn't necessarily get the same
numbers it's not trying to do you like a
like a histogram closes instrument not
trying to make a
levels
have the same number of items in
each little i think what it's doing it
speaking that range
that's the lowest point and that's the
highest point
i think it's just doing this
and we can chat actually we can
the contest
stomach of variable
when it's uh...
the room
subcommittee
most o_j_ so have dimension will be
defined amendments if you give them that
would just tell you what the shape of
that
object
so internet cut question adjust it a
little test
dataset here called b
which is just ten random
than the normal
of values
adat kat b three
and then i looked at sea
on what the levels were
sorry levels mines two point two five
minus one point five that's the first
minus one point oh five is
author of the way through
from the minimum back to the master
he's cut without telling it where you
want to break points you can actually
just get a list of these points
and that will decide that uh... that
could be really anywhere
on one of the bill
belong
to the group's define bibles
health report
thing to do that resposta
worker-friendly
the football is awesome so it overrides
playa annex lots how box and wierd if
you've got factor
groups independent variables back
it's nice to be three firms aren't
reading
an event
he's took lots of class
you know usually at st usually i don't
like it when a program tries to
guess what i'm trying to do
are almost always dresses right
equally me exactly what you think
your settled
e history
there would
there would have been waiting from the
very beginning save your whole session
to file using the same command
since i didn't to lead to do that
that way to do with and be the copy
paste what you can see in the company
uh...
nightmare for use it
that sick yep
max show equals
so if it's a history
maxed out show is a hundred
immediately jumped
uh...
well that's kind of strange
you know it is a publicity sink
our session and dot tax or something
like that
but now i can think of st
and then i could say history
max
show in personal thousands
third-party g
metafile
experimental
commit contingency
political
c history
when you go to log out ask you
if you want to say this but i guess
you know and i always ignore it
alexander
but if you say yes
it will save everything that
minister
there's a tool dot
this funny our thing
are will give you
are so did you want way of doing things
that you might want
canceled by the data frame
you have been
weighed against age
and
okay great
voters
until you learn things
but just quickly there is this question
about what tell them
that's when we return
and the state of frame
the tilbury is
um... how are represents
uh... mock essentially statistical
models who what where doing is
covered the simplest case that's saying
something is related to something else
in this case
it's just a simple um
x_y_ linear relationship
i created a simple data frame which is
sort of partly work
within them
the handout
with age and on w two here so i can say
plot
against her
and that looks like that
or
i can say plot
as a function off
now as you get
more and more into our you'll see that
till the more often
and you could do uh... use it to
actually
create statistical model objects
that are
at the conveys base for this complicated
you like
gainesville various ways
it's a first for the point one
sofas go till then at that expression
is called an arm
formulas instead of a tom
expression
and so this formula weight against age
and this case it turns out to be
you know in case a plot it
it gives you the same plot because if
you are plotted
agency expiry bowl
and we can stop by
so but if i can
if i do this week
and see what happens here
who don't know
so with skills
article since
when's it coming
again it's been a part of the
reactions to bar
david fights
wait till the ages of spitzer saying
call the formula and if you say plotted
if the same behavior
refutes that
dexter
could happen to be sorry that this is a
simple as that
you want to do it
pray
i can you do what
you want to save it okay there couple
ways one is the snow if you're working
in diabetes
here let's say there
probably pull-down menu if you're
working on the terminal like we are here
disuse one of the built-in functions
like uh...
pbf
if you're on the status of p_b_s_
so if i say pbf
and then i say plots
we do this again submissive pbf give a
file name line
plot dot
and that there's a plot
arm-in-arm a hundred
here's the trick
the dot off at the end
but you really have to do
uh... van
it makes a spot
remained
which does not display set
scott matsuda
can go back to what
you can use pbf
you conceded
you can see p_n_g_
sequences like this
whatever d devices
type back then
in this case is pbf
then do any
bunch of stuff you want to do
and the about bunch of stuff includes
graphics output
that'll go into this file
then the and use a dev dot off
to sort of weird looking
the pequots of
so any amount of stuff in between the
pediatric that off
will generate
got
i gotta go to the project
sharon k
well you've got a difference
interesting
could you've got a difference because
you generating random sequence
differently each time
yet our normal is a return normal
whatever
sm yahoo okay that's really what it's
worth it
this there shouldn't be i'm pretty sure
that single though
heart
occupiers westminster on very much
while
and see a little axe the
bike cscl i'll send those so out of a
resident
um... did you figure out what the
problem of order out of it
confusing
and if you say
if you take up with him about smu
the so strenuous super fancy here
so there's the air
from
them all
that works with the panel people's
panels useful to you
as as a regional matrix plots and
perhaps yet but the the point of the
panel
businesses and
exchanged a few years
but the point was to go inside of those
individual boxes
because lines inside there
you know remember there being a problem
before
sending another one work
or is it just for last on the top
thrilled
victory
and then you see the panel defeat that
first one with paralegals than that
so that's good
so that's uh... so the parent thing
works
this is when you say to yourself
would you say it had treason and creek
we hate to see
for a particular pursued unit
in houston
in line
means trains
uh...
yes he doesn't know
can put a number of dirt like
something common something
the working with the kids to use it
saying well forty one a plot on them
and you too
things on
this is only one of the company
so if it's a little panel
i'm not sure how to make enough
one bumpers
will benefit because they don't feel too
bad
comport with this do
trees but that's just behind me
when the press turned on
well it's probably plot dot david
touched by him or something like that
well that's the weird thing is like i
said that while most doesn't even make
any sense
was on the one i was thinkin
yet respect would just be the height
variable
yeah i don't know school like that
seniors like prompted me it's like
c
how this doesn't work
who needs it
unique dimitri too many girl was for
treatment
from now to spur on
yeah i don't know defenses type dekho
doesn't make sense and so all i can do
is try to figure out what i was
thinking original
when i mean i think the one above it
actually is
was the main point
was that
the plot
uh... the platform sham
by default
using two different as have behavior of
pop against each other
and baptist panel option
a lot to do things inside those boxes
whether the point i would be trying to
make
scrapbook
would convict her when i was thinking
islam
multi very it's scatter plots
really cold but can be kind of
parts of the great work
basic ideas you're putting every
variable test of research
set their best was
york till the flooding
z_x_ so here is just going to plot
exogenous access
wireless access
here atl plot
so it's gonna be whatever the sales
this is why mc
this is
z against x
and so on cancer down here they're gonna
be worked very
here this is
x against z like that
for that
yeltsin
but up here
x's on vertical axis then exited
so it's good to hear all possible ways
to look at them
columns of data
and some of them are factors i think
i'll do the box box char will do the box
pops up
uh... book will help it helps
it's nice that like to sort of make your
hands
and used for people who are interested
their placards that i have about a dozen
of these physical
and they're all respect for you can just
walk right through them
quicker i wanted to show you something
and that you seen this
but the hot new uh...
package now so the dismal package
it's from these the community colleges
exam species distribution guys
sachiko newmarket bite
without actually
did you are
airport testified that's great
so that's newmarket and that's my
commute to work and that's my office
and that was five months
who put me under ltd
pulled it if i mean it's about israel
trailer is already cooperative that's on
that since i don't see a warning message
yeah
geo code as part of the dismal package
yeah and i think the market new
hampshire in that pic susan's scale is
that these two code if i said
peach street newmarket new hampshire
would be more zoomed in
uh...
he just gets the extent
jeanette
creates an an map object and then fuck
done actually image for a lot is that
map sophisticated
worth what it does it gets a google map
an upcoming uppal tile but yeah i think
it's a bunch of data
so if these four lines
clinic
uh... state that make that
so if i typed p_f_ animals for lines in
the city
and annotated
and the court with courses he'd say to
you but don't they are in the the really
interesting thing is going to put their
own thing over there
look at the distance
five minutes as i saw a block this one's
plot twists from
athens he's crazy
and and but if you can still be
surprising i met with the unsurprising
you're surprised that please
retinitis happen to be honest our blog
because of the compound policy u_s_
through with the kids are upstairs
and i was down here somewhere
send from painting
visited everything you're looking at
this from this morning
this is all for this morning
yesterday that this was at the top
paid your tricks for using our dismal
and all those are stuff
so basically
it's three lines